David Metcalf

 Sacramento, California, United States

 □ david@metcalf.dev
 □ 916-701-1849
 □ in/david-codes
 □ https://metcalf.dev
 □ states

SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer with 4 years of development in modern full stack development with a focus on frontend. Proven ability to develop, implement, troubleshoot, and debug web applications. Excellent communication, problem-solving, and organizational skills. Diverse experience in engineering, marketing, and management.

EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer, 4insite

July 2024 - Present, Sacramento, CA

- Creating and enforcing code standards, delegating tasks by expertise and work load, running stand-ups.
- Collaborating with product and design leads to organize and scope our sprints and ensure timeliness of deliverables.

Software Engineer II - August 2021 - June 2024

- Building and maintaining a robust workforce management web app with over 10000 users.
- Turn UX/UI designs and User Stories into features and reusable components in React with Typescript.
- Refactoring and optimizing code for performance enhancements, reduced load times, and mobile web experience.
- Built Scope of Work and Financial dashboards with detailed charts and tables of KPIs for site managers.

Frontend Developer, Contactor, MLTwist

December 2020 - August 2021, Santa Clara, CA (remote)

- Building presentational and smart components for Machine Learning SaaS MLtwist.com.
- Creating Next.js React components and views in TypeScript following the UX design plan.
- Boosted speed of page load with server-side rendering, ensured accessibility of application for all users.

Remote Tutor, Full Stack Web Development, 2U Inc., Trilogy Education Coding Boot Camps November 2020 - May 2021, Sacramento, CA

- Weekly live one-on-one video tutoring sessions with 10+ boot camp students learning web development.
- Coach, guide and motivate students through problem solving, debugging and online research.
- Schedule, manage and host 10+ weekly sessions through Calendly and Zoom, follow up via Slack.

PROJECTS

Writistry, Markdown Microblogging App

https://github.com/gloriousLoaf/Writistry

- Full stack microblogging site with markdown posts, user profiles and admin roles.
- State managed with Redux, encrypted authorization with JSON web tokens, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Express, Node.

CartMe, E-commerce App

https://github.com/gloriousLoaf/CartMe

- Full stack e-commerce site with shopping cart, reviews, user profiles and admin roles.
- State managed with Redux, encrypted authorization with JSON web tokens, PayPal API, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Express, Node.

Emoji Runner, Desktop HTML5 Game

https://github.com/gloriousLoaf/Emoji-Runner

- Classic runner game with soundtrack and effects, secure login and score tracking.
- Engineered the in-game physics, progression, canvas, scoreboard, with P5.js, MySQL, Express, Node, Handlebars & Sequelizer.

EDUCATION

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Express, Node, MongoDB, MySQL • University of California, Davis • Davis, CA • 2020

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Express, Node, MongoDB, Python, Django, Astro, Git, GitHub, Scrum, Functional Programming, Object-oriented Programming, Accessibility, Communication, Leadership